Igor Freitas Couto

Email: igor.fcouto@gmail.com Country of residence: Brazil

Phone: +55 32 99135-6461 **Open to relocation:** Yes

SUMMARY

Full stack developer with 5 years of experience on .NET technologies and software architecture, in many segments and in companies of different sizes. I've been mainly working in cloud-based environments. Involved and committed to day-to-day work challenges and not only concerned with quality code, but also to deliver software that impacts the company and customers, following agile principles and best practices. Continuously seeks to learn and stay current with emerging technologies and trends in the software development industry.

KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS

Main Skills

.NET, C#, Web API design, ASP.NET, Test Automation (Unit, Integration and Acceptance), Postgres, SQL Server, Entity Framework Core, Dapper, Agile Methodology, Scrum Framework, Git and version control

Good Working Knowledge

AWS Cloud Services, Azure Cloud Services, Docker, CI/CD, Angular, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Redis, Kanban, Azure DevOps, GitLab, Jira, UML, Adobe Photoshop, Blender 3D, Figma

EMPLOYMENT

Lambda3 Consulting, Brazil – Software Developer Oct 2020 – Present

Bank Slip Integration:

For a fast-growing fintech I develop a system that provides businesses with a new payment option: Brazilian bank slips also known as *Boleto*.

- Software development in .NET 7.
- System design and development.
- Experience with distributed SQL database CockroachDB.
- Automated unity, functional and integration testing.
- Participating in code review and pair programming.
- SCRUM Agile Framework and ClickUp as project management tool.

Technologies and tools: .Net 6, CockroachDB, Dapper ORM, AWS Lambda Function, AWS SQS, Docker, xUnit, Integration Tests, OAuth 2, xUnit, Wiremock, Git, Git Flow, GitLab, Scrum Framework.

Cashback Wallet System:

The Wallet system allows businesses to send cashback rewards to customers in their virtual wallets. The cashback is treated exactly as real money and can be redeemed to gain discounts at selected stores.

- Software development in .NET Core 6 with minimal API.
- Web API design and development.
- Experience with distributed SQL database Postgres Citus.
- Azure Cloud infrastructure and services.
- Automated unity, functional and integration testing.
- Participating in code review and pair programming.
- SCRUM Agile Framework and AzureDevops as project management tool.

Technologies and tools: .Net 6, Postgres Citus, Entity Framework Core, Database Migrations, Azure Functions, OAuth 2, JWT Authorization Tokens, Docker, nUnit, Wiremock, Git, Azure DevOps, Scrum Framework.

Chat System Platform:

Elaboration and development of the chat and customer service system of one of the main retail chains in Brazil, which provided scale and market gain, especially during the pandemic. The chat system is integrated with WhatsApp Business API from Meta and the company's own mobile app, serving as a conversation aggregator. Seller users can perform customer services and administrative users can mass

message potential customers.

- Software development in .NET Core 3.1 and Angular 10.
- Programming and designing database NoSQL MongoDB hosted on Atlas.
- Experience in WebSockets.
- Experience in SAML (SSO).
- AWS Cloud infrastructure and services.
- Automated unity, functional and integration testing.
- SCRUM Agile Framework and Jira as project management tool.
- Participating in code review and pair programming.

Technologies and tools: Net Core 3.1, MongoDB, Redis, Database Migrations, AWS S3, AWS Lambda Functions, AWS SQS, AWS SNS, AWS API Gateway, Angular 10, SPA, HTML, SASS, npm, Docker, nUnit, Selenium, Wiremock, Git, GitLab, Jira, Scrum Framework, Figma.

Delage Logistics & Supply Chain, Brazil – Systems Analyst Mar 2018 – Oct 2020

Warehouse Management System (WMS) Platform:

Development of many features for the WMS other auxiliary software for the logistics segment. Created requirements documents, customer visit for demonstration and product deployment in Brazil and Argentina. Architecture and development of integration interfaces with third party systems (ERPs and automation).

- Software development in .NET Core 3.1, .NET Framework, Visual Basic 6, T-SQL, JavaScript, jQuery and Razor.
- Web API Development.
- Programming and designing database SQL Server.
- Experience in writing Stored Procedures, Views, Jobs, etc. (T-SQL).
- Experience in designing and developing Web services (SOAP, REST).
- Experience in deploying on-premises systems.
- Experience in customer support.

Technologies and tools: .NET Core 3.1, .NET Framework, Visual Basic 6, T-SQL, SOAP, JavaScript, jQuery, Razor, Git, Git Flow

Integration with Shuttle and Picking automation hardware:

Development of integration systems to logistics automation machinery in warehouses.

- Windows Service development.
- Experience in writing Stored Procedures (T-SQL).

- Development of complex integrations.
- Deploy on premise systems.
- On-site implementation and support.

Technologies and tools: .NET Core 3.1, .NET Framework, Windows Services, Socket TCP, SQL Server, T-SQL, Git.

Prime System Technical Courses, Brazil – Part Time Teacher Mar 2017 – Mar 2018

I taught Introduction to Programming with C#, Unity Game Engine and creating art assets. I had the opportunity to teach different kinds of people and improve my communication skills.

- Experience in dealing with young people
- Experience in creating content
- Experience in class planning

Technologies and tools: .NET Framework, Unity Game Engine, Blender 3D and Adobe Photoshop

EDUCATION

Incomplete Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

2012 - 2018

Federal University of Juiz de Fora

- Member of the junior enterprise, CODE.
- Member of the Computer Graphics, Image and Vision Group.
- Member of the Computer Science Tutorial Education Group, participating in the development of EducAR Quadrics and LocalizAR UFJF apps.
- Led a course for 40 students on 3D modeling.
- Co-authored two academic articles.

Technical certificate, Computer Assembly and Repair

2005 - 2006

Instituto Técnico Profissionalizante do Vale do Rio Preto

- Acquired comprehensive knowledge of computer hardware and software, including operating systems.
- Gained proficiency in Linux terminal usage, managing files and system processes.
- Developed skills in troubleshooting and repairing various computer issues, such as hardware malfunctions and software errors.
- Experienced in the assembly and disassembly of computer systems, understanding component compatibility, and system upgrades.

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Self-taught in many technical skills, I love to program in my free time to challenge myself.
- Motivated to explore new ideas.
- Ability to assess a situation and determine the next steps to take.
- Quickly acclimate to different environments.
- Good problem-solving skills and creative thinker.
- Open to new processes and technologies.
- Able to empathize with customers and let them know I care about their issues.

ADDITIONAL

English Certification ETS - TOEFL iBT - Certified 2022, Scored 91 of 120

Co-author of two academic publications:

(2019) EducAR – Quadrics: A Tool to Aid teaching of Calculus through Augmented

Reality – Brazilian Journal of Computers in Education (Revista Brasileira de Informática na Educação – RBIE), 27(2), 198-217. DOI: 10.5753/RBIE.2019.27.02.198. [Link]

(2017) A Tool to Aid teaching of Calculus through Augmented

Reality — XXVIII Brazilian Symposium on Computers in Education (XXVIII Simpósio Brasileiro De Informática Na Educação - SBIE), DOI: 10.5753/cbie.sbie.2017.595. [Link]

GitHub Profile:

https://github.com/igor-couto